## **EFE FORTUNE SAMUEL**

## **Application Developer**

**Email**: samuelefe.37@gmail.com **Phone**: +234 706 789 6171

Portfolio: https://www.efesamuel.netlify.app/

#### **ABOUT ME:**

I am a professional developer, I develop fully responsive applications using modern technologies such as **Javascript Es6+**, **React.js**, **Node.js**, **Express js**, **HTML5**, **CSS3** and a host of other technologies while consistently receiving high user experience score for all my web development projects. Below, you'd find some projects I have completed that showcase my skills and general background in web development.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE:**

# SANLAM NIGERIA APPLICATION DEVELOPER:

**OCTOBER 2022 - PRESENT:** 

- I created a notification service that automatically retrieved clients' personal
  information and sends them a personalized message on their birthdays. Additionally,
  the system sends notifications about insurance premiums that are due. The service was
  built with Node JS and hosted on AWS, ensuring reliability and scalability.
- I developed a sales website for life insurance that streamlined the process of buying
  life insurance policies. The website is designed to be user-friendly and easy to
  navigate, making it simple for users to obtain insurance quotes and purchase policies.
- I developed a robust and user-friendly application that enables clients to easily and seamlessly insure their vehicles through brokers. The app's intuitive interface makes it easy for customers to obtain insurance quotes and complete the purchase process.
- I participated in developing a real-time claims app that uses video calling to streamline
  the motor claims process for a company, resulting in faster claims processing for
  customers. By allowing customers to connect with the back office staff in real-time, we
  are able to inspect damages and process claims faster than ever before

# PRECISE FINANCIAL SYSTEMS SOFTWARE SPECIALIST/DATABASE ADMINISTRATOR: FEBRUARY 2022 - OCTOBER 2022:

- I work with my team to enhance the company's software and ensure maximum stability and user experience.
- Effectively manage the database of leading African financial institutions that are currently running the company's financial software (CLIREC).
- Facilitation of trainings for the users and technical team on the usage of various company products/software.
- Investigating, troubleshooting, analysis and solving of reported issues by the clients.

#### **EDDIESOFT BUSINESS SYSTEMS**

#### FRONTEND DEVELOPER:

#### **NOVEMBER 2018 - JANUARY 2022:**

- Built efficient, testable and reusable React JS applications and modules.
- Collaborated with developers in remote locations to implement web designs that caters for up to 1000 visitors.
- Redesigned and improved websites of companies to be fully responsive to every design types and screen sizes.
- Developed fully responsive CRUD (Create, Read, Update, Delete) web applications.

#### SIMPLEX BUSINESS SOLUTIONS

#### **DEVELOPER INTERN:**

#### **JANUARY 2018 - SEPTEMBER 2018:**

- Configured and customized existing web applications according to client specifications.
- Provided innovative ideas to the leadership team while also working with Project manager to ensure project completion within budgetary and time constraints.
- Worked extensively with the design team and design tools (Invision, Sketch, Figma) to deliver responsive web designs to all screens.
- Participated in brainstorming and other idea-generating team sessions.

#### **PROJECTS:**

#### **Buyinsurance** (http://buyinsurance.sanlam.com.ng/)

This is a sales website for life insurance that streamlines the process of buying life insurance policies. The website is designed to be user-friendly and easy to navigate, making it simple for users to obtain insurance quotes and purchase policies.

**Developed with:** React Js, Javascript, Node js, Express js, HTML5, CSS3.

#### E-Streams | Movies & TV Series (https://estreams.netlify.app/)

See the full details & trailers of your favourite movies, latest movies and tv series. It Utilizes the TMDB api so the movies on the application are always up to date!

**Developed with:** React Js, Javascript, HTML5, CSS3.

#### **Top Invoice (https://topinvoice.netlify.app/)**

Top Invoice is a web application used to **create**, **store**, **manage**, and **delete** invoices for your business. it is an application that is ready for use by businesses or companies!

Developed with: React Js, Javascript, Express js, HTML5, CSS3.

#### E-Countries (https://e-countries.netlify.app/)

This web application contains the details of every single country on earth and 1000+ facts of all countries on earth. Search for any country and get to know more about the country! It utilizes the restcountries **API** to get information about countries via a RESTful API **Developed with**: React Js, Javascript, HTML5, CSS3.

#### **EDUCATION:**

#### 2014 - 2019 | Olabisi Onabanjo University

**Bachelor of Computer Science** 

#### **SKILLS:**

Frontend: Javascript, Reactjs, React native, Vue js, HTML5, CSS3

Backend: NodeJs, ExpressJs

Database: Microsoft SQL Server, MySQL, MongoDb

Version Control: Git, Github

Design: Figma, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe XD, Photoshop